<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mindset on Ben Mezger</title><link>https://benmezger.github.io/tags/mindset/</link><description>Recent content in mindset on Ben Mezger</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 08:55:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benmezger.github.io/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Communication</title><link>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/communication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 08:55:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/communication/</guid><description>Backlinks # Nonviolent communication: A language for life</description></item><item><title>Socratic questioning</title><link>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/socratic-questioning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 10:16:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/socratic-questioning/</guid><description>Backlinks # Thinking methods tags Thinking methods Mindset Mental models Learning Socratic questioning is one of many Mental models allows us to pursue thoughts in many directions and establish first principles through strict analysis. It allows us to establish truth and separate knowledge from ignorance by reveling underlying assumptions. The method allows us to explore complex ideas and find the truth out of things while opening up issues and problems.</description></item><item><title>Mental models</title><link>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/mental-models/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 01:30:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/mental-models/</guid><description>Backlinks # Thinking methods The great mental models: General thinking concepts Socratic questioning tags Thinking methods Mindset Learning « You only think you know, as a matter of fact. And most of your actions are based on incomplete knowledge and you really don’t know what it is all about, or what the purpose of the world is, or know a great deal of other things.</description></item><item><title>Mindset</title><link>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/mindset/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 01:24:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/mindset/</guid><description>Backlinks # Nonviolent communication: A language for life Thinking methods Mental models The great mental models: General thinking concepts Socratic questioning</description></item><item><title>Thinking methods</title><link>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/thinking-methods/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 01:19:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/thinking-methods/</guid><description>Backlinks # Mental models The great mental models: General thinking concepts Socratic questioning tags Learning Mindset Mental models Thinking methods are techniques where we can get better at solving complex problems and having a clearer view of the problem. It allows us to thought experience and running towards reality instead of away from. Understanding must constantly be tested against reality and updated accordingly. We can break problems into sub-problems so we can better view reality.</description></item><item><title>The great mental models: General thinking concepts</title><link>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/the-great-mental-models/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 20:03:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://benmezger.github.io/notes/the-great-mental-models/</guid><description>Backlinks # Mental models tags Thinking methods Mental models Mindset Learning READ The Great Mental Models: General Thinking Concepts #</description></item></channel></rss>